Save the Vault. Tell the Story.
Zappa is a music, documentary film directed by Alex Winter.
With the help of more than 10,000 dedicated Zappa fans, this is the long-awaited definitive documentary project
of Alex Winter documenting the life and career of enigmatic groundbreaking rock star Frank Zappa.
Alex also utilizes in this picture thousands of hours of painstakingly digitized videos,
photos, audio, writing, and everything in between from Zappa's private archives.
These chronicles have never been brought to a public audience before, until now.
Self (archive footage), played by Frank Zappa.
Self - Played with Zappa 1987-1988, played by Mike Keneally.
Self - Author, Former Member of the GTOs, played by Pamela Des Barres.
Self - Newscaster for Action News (archive footage), played by Lonnie Lardner.
Self - Frank Zappa's Sister (archive footage), played by Patrice Zappa.
Self - Frank Zappa's Mother (archive footage), played by Rose Zappa.
Zappa is an American documentary film about the musician Frank Zappa.
Directed by Alex Winter, it was released on November 27, 2020.
Frank Zappa (1940–1993) was an American composer, bandleader, and guitarist.
Best known for writing and performing a large body of unconventional rock music
and releasing many albums, his work combined multiple music genres.
He held iconoclastic views about music, the music
industry, and American culture and politics.
The Zappa documentary tells the story of his life and career.
Director Alex Winter had free access to Zappa's extensive archives.
The film includes footage of performances by Zappa and his various bands, as
well as many interviews of people who knew or worked with him.
In addition to Zappa himself, the interview subjects include Bruce Bickford, Pamela Des Barres, Bunk Gardner,
Mike Keneally, Scott Thunes, Ian Underwood, Ruth Underwood, Steve Vai, Ray White, and Gail Zappa.
The film explores themes of composer, biography,
avant-garde, progressive rock, rock singer.